<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kubernetes on Andy Roberts</title>
    <link>https://www.andyroberts.nz/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kubernetes on Andy Roberts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 11:36:54 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.andyroberts.nz/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>KubeCon &amp; CloudNative Con North America 2024 </title>
      <link>https://www.andyroberts.nz/posts/kubecon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 11:36:54 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.andyroberts.nz/posts/kubecon/</guid>
      <description>Well, the last week has been a whirlwind as I was fortunate to attend KubeCon + CloudNativeCon in Salt Lake City, Utah. Being based in New Zealand means we have few choices for conferences, so being able to attend KubeCon for the first time was a real eye opener.
Flying into Salt Lake City after 27 hours of travel from New Zealand, the snowcapped peaks of the Wasatch Mountains were a real treat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CKA Exam Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.andyroberts.nz/posts/cka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 20:30:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.andyroberts.nz/posts/cka/</guid>
      <description>The Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) had been on my radar for a while, but my passion for not enjoying exams kept from committing to it. But after running into some curly Kubernetes issues at work I decided I would give it a try as even if I failed, the learning aspect of it would be most valuable.
Background - I use Kubernetes, well AKS, A LOT in my day job. I am part of a team which designs/deploys/manages around 30 AKS clusters in many different regions, with lots of different workloads on them, plus also chucking in the dreaded Windows node pools for good measure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Velero for AKS Cross Region Disaster Recovery</title>
      <link>https://www.andyroberts.nz/posts/velero-aks-regional-dr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 11:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.andyroberts.nz/posts/velero-aks-regional-dr/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I wrote a blog post, but I wanted to jump back in again with big one, Disaster Recovery!
Traditionally with DR in a Virtual Machine infrastructure, you would replicate the VMs/Disks etc to your DR location, and when you initial a failover you simply start them up. This works well in a VM environment because you would normally spend a fair amount of time configuring them, either manually (I hope not) or with Automation, but either way its time consuming but well understood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating an AKS Release Pipeline in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.andyroberts.nz/posts/aks-cicd-azuredevops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 21:36:09 +1300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.andyroberts.nz/posts/aks-cicd-azuredevops/</guid>
      <description>AKS and Kubernetes in general is still fairly new to me, but its something I am using more and more every day. One of the challenges I have faced is that the more I have to deploy to is, is the need for a simple way to deploy a set of apps you need on every cluster, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve a complicated solution. I am an &amp;lsquo;Ops&amp;rsquo; guy by trade so creating release artifacts and NuGet packages doesn&amp;rsquo;t come naturally too me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTTPS to AKS with Traefik and Lets Encrypt</title>
      <link>https://www.andyroberts.nz/posts/aks-traefik-https/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 15:10:24 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.andyroberts.nz/posts/aks-traefik-https/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll preface this blog post with the fact that I am FAR FAR away from any kind of expert on Kubernetes and AKS. I am still very early in my journey with it, and a lot of my experience so far is trial and error. I have also found that there is a lot of documentation out there on how to do things, but a lot of it assumes a fairly decent knowledge of how everything sticks together, so for a newbie to Kubernetes it can be quite challenging.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
